Gabriel Emilio López Ojeda

81 8023 6577

□ lopez.ojeda.gabriel.emilio@gmail.com

Portfolio in linkedin.com/gabriel-emilio-lopez-ojeda github.com/Canciller

Professional profile

I am a software engineer with expertise in both web and mobile development. My skill set includes working with React and Node.js technologies, including Next.js and Remix.js, as well as developing mobile applications using React Native and native code for library development when necessary. As a curious and eager learner, I continuously seek opportunities to grow. I highly value collaboration and teamwork, which are essential qualities in my professional approach.

Experience

HPMLED April 2024 - May 2024

Freelance Remote

• Developed new website on Shopify utilizing React/Remix/Hydrogen, effectively enhancing the company's online visibility by replacing an outdated and neglected site (www.hpmled.com).

INTELA Servicios Corporativos

October 2021 - March 2024

Software Engineer Remote

- Led the development of a React Native mobile app, deployed on App Store and Play Store. The app simplified employee tasks, resulting in quicker leave requests, better attendance tracking, and easier access to company news.
- Contributed to the development of an administrative panel using Next.js. This panel managed roles, permissions, and data displayed in the mobile app.
- Contributed to the development of the front-end of an internal mobile app that managed invoices using React Native, focusing on integration with back-end services.
- Utilized Strapi (CMS) within the administrative panel, primarily to facilitate easy management of resources such as images, videos, and articles authored by non-developers.
- Created multiple scripts to massively handle and load data to databases from JSON or XLSX files.
- Created multiple cloud functions using Firebase.
- Managed deployment of mobile apps in App Store Connect, and Google Play Console.
- Managed deployment of cloud functions using Firebase.
- Fixed and debugged errors in code and deployments.

Baja Ferries (assigned through the consulting firm Bikey)

May 2021 - October 2021

Monterrey, N.L.

 Contributed to the development of a travel expenses website using SAP Gateway with an ODATA API for the back-end and SAPUI5 for the front-end, deployed on-premise to the SAP Fiori launchpad.

PIASA (assigned through the consulting firm Dobresoft)

October 2020 - March 2021

Software engineer intern

Software engineer intern

Monterrey, N.L

 Contributed in the development of a website to track expenses against departmental budgets. Extracted data from SAP ECC to an SQL database. The back-end was built with Node.js and Express, and the front-end with React.

Education

Universidad Autónoma de Nuevo León

August 2017 - August 2022

Bachelor of Software Engineering

Monterrey, N.L.

• Relevant Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms, Software Foundations, Computer Architecture, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Architecture

Technical Skills

Languages: TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, Java, Go, Lua, Bash, SQL, HTML, CSS

Technologies: React.js, React Native, Next.js, Remix, Shopify Hydrogen, Express.js, Node.js, Electron, Tailwind, GraphQL

Databases: MongoDB, Postgres, MS-SQL

Tools: Git, Postman, Figma

DevOps: Docker, GCP Cloud, AWS Lambda, Firebase Functions, Firebase Hosting, Vercel, Linux (configuring and

managing)

Others: Data Modeling, Agile, Scrum, SOLID, Design Patterns, Debugging, Root Cause Analysis, Web Development,

Front-End, Back-End